Dainese is a company that mainly works and produces technical equipment for motorcyclists,
and not only, but also for technical equipment for skiing, for the bike and for equipping.
Before the introduction of 3D, I mainly used Adobe Illustrator and developed the whole process,
the whole work process at a creative level, always with Adobe Illustrator.
After that, I spent my time with Adobe Illustrator.
I created a sketch for the product technicians and modelers,
and from there began the whole process of product development,
the creation of model cards, the creation of the first prototype, corrections and the whole work process.
We mainly adopted a 3D solution within the work process,
more than anything else to, one,
to quickly interpret the ideas of the style office,
to present the development of the projects in a clear and useful way to everyone,
to reduce the number of prototypes, also for a course of sustainability,
and also to reduce the time for the definition of the prototype.
How did you start 3D?
From the moment we introduced 3D,
within the work process,
we have really found many advantages,
especially a reduction of time for the definition of the prototype,
because, let's say, from the moment I develop the sketch with 3D,
or in any case I develop the project with 3D,
the advantage is that the product technicians, modelers,
already find the model cards made.
I'm not saying that I replace their work,
but it's a big advantage for them,
it's also a big advantage on my part,
to already have the product with all the proportions in place.
What is the big difference between 3D and 3D?
In terms of prototypes,
let's say that the big difference with 3D is that,
not always,
but in 90% of the cases,
we arrive at the final product with the first prototype,
while before, working with Adobe Illustrator and with the two-dimensional,
we needed a little more prototypes,
we also needed two, three, if not four prototypes.
What is the difference between 3D and 3D?
Let's say that 3D has been,
3D has been a big help for all the parts of the company,
not only the style part,
because with 3D,
you actually already see the almost realistic product
even before it comes out,
so even people who are not used to seeing,
let's say, the two-dimensional sketches,
seeing them in three-dimensional,
it has a whole different taste,
let's call it that.
Even at a decision-making level,
we manage to have some decisions anticipated
compared to the two-dimensional.
I repeat, it was all to our advantage.
What solutions have you seen compared to Claw?
We had seen other solutions compared to Claw,
but at a visual level,
and also at a level of ease of use,
we chose Claw,
precisely for the reasons I have just mentioned.
Because we say that Claw is not an excessively technical program
that is possible to use even without having solid models.
And so we chose it precisely for this reason
and to implement it first of all in the creative part,
and not only,
because currently in the company,
not only the designers have Claw,
but also some modelers.
What are your plans for the future?
We intend to implement more 3D in the future,
not only in our area,
but also as a help,
or in any case to develop it
to support marketing,
as in e-commerce.
What are your plans for the future?
We hope this 3D platform will be useful
to enable this new technology
and further advance our business
and our business perspective.
Can you suggest a solution
in the future?
We are trying to find a way
to support our customers
through a more specific and
collaborative approach.
How to get in contact with Claw in person?
We will write you a feedback
about Claw's product or sales,
this is our first step,
and we will try to ask you
if you have any questions.
In the future,
in the future,